德约科维奇 4-6 6-4 6-4 兹维列夫 · 赛后场上采访
Huge congratulations.
热烈祝贺你
The streak in Beijing continues.
你在北京的连胜还在继续
Tell us what was the essential part
你觉得今晚从落后一盘
of your tennis coming
到最终逆转
from a set down tonight?
网球方面的关键是什么？
I had a terrible start, you know,
我的开局很糟 你知道
two double faults in the beginning.
一上来就有两个双误
It was quite cold.
天气挺冷的
Honestly, I didn't feel warmed up,
说实话 我感觉还没热开
but my fault, you know,
但这是我的问题
gave him an early break and then it was hard
早早让他破发之后
to come back in the first set.
第一盘就很难追回来了
I had some couples break points
我有过几个破发点
to break him back when he was serving
想在他发球胜盘局回破
for a set, a 5 -4, didn't use that.
当时5比4 但我没抓住
But then I kind of felt already
不过我已经感觉到
from the midway first set,
从第一盘中段开始
I was starting to get a good rhythm,
我逐渐找到了不错的节奏
at least on my serve, serve plus one.
至少发球加第一拍是这样
I was trying to be aggressive
我试着打得更主动
and come to the net and, you know,
也尝试上网 你知道
change up the pace, you know,
改变节奏
not give him the same pattern,
不给他相同的套路
you know, and he's the best player
他现在是世界上
in the world at the moment, for sure,
最好的球员 毫无疑问
in a huge run and confidence role.
连胜势头强劲 信心十足
So, you know, when he's serving
所以当他发球
the way he was serving tonight or whatever,
像今晚这样 或者说
the whole year, it's just a nightmare
这一整年这样 对对手来说
for the opponent, you know,
简直就是噩梦
you don't have too many opportunities.
你不会有太多机会
And when they're presented,
而机会出现时
if you don't use them, it's frustrating.
如果没抓住 会很沮丧
So I'm just glad that, you know,
所以我很高兴
I kind of held my nerves, played, you know,
自己稳住了情绪
I guess, good shots and read his serve
打出好球 也读懂了他的发球
in important moments on 5 -4
在5比4的关键时刻
and both second and third.
第二盘和第三盘都是如此
But I think I would highlight
不过我想特别提到
my serve plus one, you know,
我的发球加第一拍
that was pretty accurate today.
今天打得相当精准
You keep on doing it, here you are, 39.
你还在做到这一点 已39岁
I mean,
我是说
it hasn't always been easy for you this year,
今年对你来说并不总是轻松
but you've achieved another terrific victory.
但你又拿下了一场精彩的胜利
What's it like?
这是什么感受？
I mean, to be honest, these are kind
说实话 就是这些时刻
of moments that I still play for, compete for.
时刻 让我仍然打球 竞争
I mean, motivation is big, obviously,
显然 这给我很大的动力
when you're feeling good and competing
当你感觉不错 能够
at par with the best players in the world
和世界顶尖球员势均力敌
and in front of 15,000 people, of course.
当然 还有现场一万五千人
You know, these are the kind of moments
你知道 就是这样的时刻
that define dreams of, I think,
我想 构成了
every tennis player.
每个网球运动员的梦想
So, yeah, I mean,
所以 是啊
it's been a struggle this year,
今年确实很艰难
to be honest, for different reasons,
说实话 有各种原因
but I'm still there, I'm still grinding,
但我还在这里 还在努力
I'm still making the youngsters work
我还在让这些年轻人
for their money and I'm just glad to push it
必须拼尽全力 很高兴我能
through.
挺过来
Long may I continue, well done.
愿你继续下去 干得漂亮
Thank you.
谢谢